dealsdirect.com.au 2014-12-24

# Deals Direct Privacy Policy

  * Introduction
  * Security of your Personal Information
  * Kind of personal information DD collects and holds
  * How Personal Information is collected and held
  * Purposes for which DD collects, holds, uses and discloses Personal Information
  * Cookies
  * Accessing and seeking correction of your personal information
  * Pseudonyms
  * DD's access to your information
  * Third Party access to your information
  * Overseas Disclosures
  * Disclosure of personal information to an overseas recipient as required or authorised by law
  * Changes to Our Privacy Policy
  * Consequences for you if your personal information is not provided to us
  * Using and disclosing information for direct marketing
  * Requests by you to stop direct marketing communications
  * Destroying or de-identifying personal information
  * Verifying your identity
  * Refusal to give access
  * Privacy Complaints

**Introduction**

Australian Privacy laws have changed. All organisations that collect personal or sensitive data must do so in compliance with the Australian Privacy Principles which came into effect March 12 2014. This includes your consent for DealsDirect's use of your personal details to process and fulfil your order as well as service your account.

DealsDirect.com.au ABN 64 096 509 134 ("DealsDirect") is an online retailer and is committed to protecting your privacy and developing a website that gives you an enjoyable and secure online experience. In this Privacy Policy, when the words "we", "us" or "DD" are used, they are references to DealsDirect. In all dealings by us involving the collection, storage and use of customers' personal information, DD will comply with its obligations under the Australian Privacy Principles ("APPs") prescribed by the Privacy Amendment (Enhancing Privacy Protection) Act 2012 (the "Act"). DD has taken and will continue to take reasonable steps to:

  * implement practices, procedures and systems that will ensure that we comply with the APPs and any binding registered APP code; and
  * be able to deal with privacy related inquiries and complaints in a prompt manner.

Note: 'Personal information' is defined in the Act as 'information or an opinion about an identified individual, or an individual who is reasonably identifiable:

  * whether the information or opinion is true or not, and
  * whether the information or opinion is recorded in a material form or not.

**Security of your Personal Information**

DD has implemented security systems for protecting your personal information from misuse, interference and loss and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. This is done using information technology security systems, strictly monitored internal staff access controls, ongoing staff privacy training and privacy audits. DD also has established procedures for identifying and reporting privacy breaches and for receiving and responding to complaints and inquiries. DD has also adopted a program of periodic review of the adequacy and currency of our Privacy Policy and of the practices, procedures and systems implemented under it.

**Kind of personal information DD collects and holds**

DD collects and holds personal information such as you name, postal address, delivery address, email address, telephone numbers and computer cookies. DD does not retain credit card or bank account details. These details are permanently destroyed by DD after we process your payment.

**How personal information is collected and held**

DD collects and stores your personal information whenever:

  * you register an account with us;
  * You subscribe to our newsletter
  * you visit or place an order to purchase a product on www.dealsdirect.com.au;
  * you send us an email;
  * you enter a competition; or
  * you purchase a voucher from us.

Your personal information is stored and secured using our third party data storage provider.

Purposes for which DD collects, holds, uses and discloses personal information DD collects, holds, uses and discloses your personal information for the primary purpose of:

  * processing your order for products;
  * ensuring that your products are properly delivered to you;
  * properly managing and fulfilling product returns or refunds;
  * receiving and resolving complaints;
  * allowing third party service providers to manage the services provided to you;
  * mailing and delivery systems for products you have purchased;
  * maintenance and repair services;
  * market research;
  * marketing activities conducted by DD or any of our related companies; and
  * our professional advisers, accountants, lawyers, auditors.

We may also use your personal information for the secondary purpose of sending you offers to purchase further products or to inform you about competitions that DD may conduct. Any offers sent to you by DD will contain a clear and easy-to-read "opt-out" button which you can use to stop DD from sending you such offers in the future.

**Cookies**

This website uses "cookies" to help you personalise your online experience. A cookie is a text file or a packet of information that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server to identify and interact more effectively with your computer. There are two types of cookies that may be used at the DealsDirect.com.au website: a persistent cookie and a session cookie. A persistent cookie gets entered by your web browser into the "Cookies" folder on your computer and remains in this "Cookies" folder after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. A session cookie is held temporarily in your computer's memory and disappears after you close your browser or shut down your computer. The DealsDirect.com.au website may also use web "beacons" (also called "clear GIFs" or "pixel tags") in conjunction with cookies for the same reasons. Web beacons are small strings of code that are placed in a Web page. Cookies cannot be used to run programs. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time.

The purpose of a cookie is to tell the web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalise DD pages, or register with the DealsDirect.com.au website or services, the cookie helps DD record your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same DD website, information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the DD features that you customised. You can configure your internet browser (such as Microsoft Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox, or Safari) to accept all cookies, reject all cookies or notify you when a cookie is sent. Please refer to your internet browsers instructions to learn more about these functions. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies, if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the DD services or websites you visit.

**Accessing and seeking correction of your personal information**

Customers can gain access to or seek the correction of the personal information that DD holds. DD customers have a right to make a reasonable request for access to their personal information and to request its correction. Requests to access or seek to correct your personal information can be made by email to the Privacy Officer at privacy@dealsdirect.com.au or by contacting our Privacy Officer on 029641 2222 When we receive such a request, we have the right to ask for and obtain your position title, telephone number and email address in order for you to access and correct personal information.

**Pseudonyms**

A person can deal with DD by not identifying themselves or using a pseudonym. The circumstances under which a customer can use only a pseudonym are:

  * (a) Placing a review or providing feedback on a review
  * (b) Submitting a support request not order or account related.

If you are required to complete an online form which will include your personal information, we will offer you an accessible link to an "APP 5 notice", and you will be required to confirm that you have reviewed the notice before providing us with your personal information. If we collect your personal information by telephone, we will explain the APP 5 matters to you at the commencement of the call.

**DD's access to your information**

DD staff that will have access to your personal information after it is collected will include:

  * DealsDirect Administrative
  * DealsDirect Warehouse personnel

DD staff authorised to access your personal information are trained in compliance with the Act and have access only to carry out the primary purpose See above).

**Third Party Access to your information**

The following third party recipients may have access to your personal information for the primary purposes noted above:

  * Mailing and delivery system providers such as couriers and Australia Post.
  * Email & newsletter service providers
  * Independent reviewing platform providers
  * Drop ship suppliers
  * Marketing affiliates
  * Maintenance and repair service providers

**Overseas disclosures**

We may need (or be required) to disclose your personal information to an overseas entity only to the extent to which such disclosure is required to enable us to carry out the primary purpose of processing, fulfilling or the post purchase support of your order. We do not record and therefore will never disclose any financial information such as credit card or bank account details to any overseas entity.

Dealsdirect may transfer your personal information to an overseas recipient in circumstances where:

  * The business service provider is located overseas
  * We are required to comply with a foreign legal or regulatory request
  * You have ordered a product provided directly by an International supplier - a Direct Import product.

This may mean that your information is stored on a server located outside of Australia. Any such disclosures will be to providers located in the USA and Asia Pacific (including but not limited to Hong Kong, China and Sri Lanka)

While all care is taken to ensure our overseas providers will handle your information securely, by consenting to this disclosure you acknowledge that:

  * Overseas recipients may not have the same privacy obligations provided by the APP's and therefore redress options may differ or not be available to you.
  * Overseas recipients may be subject to foreign laws that require disclosure to an overseas authority.
  * DealsDirect will not be held accountable for any breaches of the APP's by an overseas recipient nor will any redress options apply under the Privacy Act.

**Disclosure of personal information to an overseas recipient as required or authorised by law**

DD may disclose personal information to an overseas recipient without complying with the APPs where the disclosure is required or authorised by or under an Australian law or a court/tribunal order. Examples of where a law or order may require or authorise disclosure of personal information to an overseas recipient are:

  * DD disclosing personal information to the government of a foreign country under the Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorism Financing Act 2006 (Cth); or
  * DD disclosing personal information to an overseas recipient under the Australian Federal Police Act 1979 or the Mutual Assistance in Criminal Matters Act 1987 (Cth).

**Length of time Personal Information is retained**

DD will keep and retain your personal information for a period of 10 years, or such other period of time as is required by Law.

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**

DD updates its Privacy Policy from time to time, as and when the Act is amended. We notify our customers of changes to our Privacy Policy by asking them to agree to the new policies when they next place an order. Alternatively, we may post a link on the website headed "Changes to our Privacy Policy" for customers to read.

**Consequences for you if your personal information is not provided to us**

If some or all of the personal information that we request is not provided to us, the main consequence is that we may not be able to fulfil your order or to deliver your products to you. Other consequences may include that we might not be able to resolve any complaint you have against DD.

<strongUsing and disclosing personal information for direct marketing

DD may use or disclose personal information about you for the purpose of direct marketing if:

  * DD collected the information from you;
  * you would reasonably expect DD to use or disclose the information for that purpose;
  * DD provides you with an option to 'opt-out' of receiving direct marketing communications from us, and
  * you have not made such an 'opt-out' request to us.

**Requests by you to stop direct marketing communications**

If DD uses or discloses your personal information for the purpose of direct marketing, you may request not to receive direct marketing communications from us. DD will not charge you for making or giving effect to your data and we will stop sending direct marketing communications within a reasonable period after your request is made (usually within 5 working days from receiving your request).

You may also ask us to identify the source of the personal information. DD will notify you of the source, unless this is impracticable or unreasonable, which will depend on a number of factors, including:

  * the consequences for you if you are not notified of the source;
  * the length of time that has elapsed since the personal information was collected by us;
  * the time and cost involved.

**Destroying or de-identifying personal information**

DD will take reasonable steps to destroy or de-identify personal information it holds if it no longer needs the information for any purpose for which it may be used or disclosed under the APPs. The requirement to take reasonable steps to destroy or de-identify does not apply if personal information is contained in a Commonwealth record, or if an Australian law or a court/tribunal order requires it to be retained.

**Verifying your identity**

DD must be satisfied that a request for personal information made by the individual concerned, or by another person who is authorised to make a request on their behalf, for example, as a legal guardian or authorised agent. It would generally be extremely difficult for DD to deal with an anonymous request for personal information. However, it may be practicable to deal with a pseudonymous request, for example, where you have previously transacted under that pseudonym and can establish your identity as that individual. The steps required for DD to verify your identity will depend on the circumstances. In particular, whether you are already known to or readily identifiable by DD. The minimum amount of personal information needed to establish your identity will be sought. In a telephone call DD may request information that can be checked against records held by us, such as your date of birth or address.

**Refusal to give Access**

Whilst every effort will be made by DD to provide access in a manner that is as prompt, uncomplicated and inexpensive as possible, DD may refuse to give you access to your personal information. There are a number of grounds upon which DD can refuse to give you access to your personal information. These reasons may include (without limitation):

  * if DD reasonably believes that giving access would pose a serious threat to the life, health or safety of any individual, or to public health or public safety;
  * giving access would have an unreasonable impact on the privacy of other individuals;
  * the request for access is frivolous or vexatious;
  * the information relates to existing or anticipated legal proceedings between you and DD, and would not be accessible by the process of discovery in those proceedings;
  * giving access would reveal the intentions of DD in relation to negotiations with you in such a way as to prejudice those negotiations;
  * giving access would be unlawful;
  * denying access is required or authorised by or under an Australian law or a court/tribunal order;
  * DD has reason to suspect that unlawful activity, or misconduct of a serious nature, that relates to DD's functions or activities has been, is being or may be engaged in and giving access would be likely to prejudice the taking of appropriate action in relation to the matter;
  * giving access would be likely to prejudice one or more enforcement related activities conducted by, or on behalf of, an enforcement body; or
  * giving access would reveal evaluative information generated within DD in connection with a commercially sensitive decision making process.

**Privacy Complaints**

An individual can complain about an alleged breach by DD of the APPs by sending an email to the Privacy Officer at privacy@dealsdirect.com.au setting out details of the complaint. Alternatively, the Privacy Officer can be contacted by telephoning 02 9641 2222 or by sending a letter with details of your complaint to:

The Privacy Officer  
Deals Direct Pty Limited  
5 Inglis Road,  
Ingleburn NSW 2170

All complaints are required by the Act to be made in writing to DD and DD is then allowed a reasonable time (usually 30 days) to respond to complaints. We may ask you to participate in a dispute resolution scheme (such as mediation) in order to resolve your complaint. If you refuse to participate in any form of dispute resolution, you can take your complaint to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (OAIC) by calling 1300 363 992 or logging on to the OAIC website at: http://www.oaic.gov.au/

×

* New subscribers only. $50 minumum spend. See Welcome email for details.

No thanks, I'm already a member

To redeem your offer, simply enter the coupon code **LOVEDEALS** when you are ready to checkout to have the discount applied.

The offer is only valid for the email address 

A Direct Import Product is offered directly from an overseas Supplier. Goods or multiples of goods with a total cost under $1000 are generally exempt from GST. It is recommended that you read the information on the “Direct Import” tab so you are aware of your Direct Importer obligations prior to purchase.

View Direct Import terms & conditions.

**Shipping Promotions**

DealsDirect may at its discretion run shipping promotions from time to time offering shipping discounts or free shipping. Unfortunately we are unable to offer promotional shipping to all locations in Australia.

**The following remote postcodes are excluded from any shipping promotions:**

###  Northern Territory Remote

800, 801, 803, 804, 810, 811, 812, 813, 814, 815, 820, 821, 822, 828, 829, 830, 831, 832, 834, 835, 836, 837, 838, 839, 840, 841, 845, 846, 847, 850, 851, 852, 853, 854, 860, 861, 862, 870, 871, 872, 873, 880, 881, 885, 886, 906, 907, 909

###  New South Wales Remote

2898, 2899

###  Queensland Remote

4183, 4184, 4481, 4482, 4486, 4487, 4488, 4489, 4490, 4491, 4492, 4493, 4700, 4741, 4801, 4802, 4803, 4807, 4816, 4819, 4828, 4829, 4830, 4871, 4873, 4874, 4875, 4876, 4890, 4891, 4895

###  Western Australia Remote

6161, 6207, 6208, 6209, 6210, 6211, 6213, 6214, 6215, 6218, 6220, 6221, 6223, 6224, 6225, 6226, 6227, 6228, 6229, 6230, 6231, 6232, 6233, 6236, 6237, 6239, 6240, 6243, 6244, 6251, 6252, 6253, 6254, 6255, 6256, 6258, 6260, 6262, 6271, 6275, 6280, 6281, 6282, 6284, 6285, 6286, 6288, 6290, 6302, 6304, 6306, 6308, 6309, 6311, 6312, 6313, 6315, 6316, 6317, 6318, 6320, 6321, 6322, 6323, 6324, 6326, 6327, 6328, 6330, 6331, 6332, 6333, 6335, 6336, 6337, 6338, 6341, 6343, 6346, 6348, 6350, 6351, 6352, 6353, 6355, 6356, 6357, 6358, 6359, 6361, 6363, 6365, 6367, 6368, 6369, 6370, 6372, 6373, 6375, 6383, 6384, 6385, 6386, 6390, 6391, 6392, 6393, 6394, 6395, 6396, 6397, 6398, 6401, 6403, 6405, 6407, 6409, 6410, 6411, 6412, 6413, 6414, 6415, 6418, 6419, 6420, 6421, 6422, 6423, 6424, 6425, 6426, 6427, 6428, 6429, 6430, 6431, 6432, 6433, 6434, 6436, 6437, 6438, 6440, 6442, 6443, 6445, 6446, 6447, 6448, 6450, 6452, 6460, 6461, 6462, 6463, 6465, 6466, 6467, 6468, 6470, 6472, 6473, 6475, 6476, 6477, 6479, 6480, 6484, 6485, 6487, 6488, 6489, 6490, 6501, 6502, 6503, 6504, 6505, 6506, 6507, 6509, 6510, 6511, 6512, 6513, 6514, 6515, 6516, 6517, 6518, 6519, 6521, 6522, 6525, 6528, 6530, 6531, 6532, 6535, 6536, 6537, 6556, 6558, 6560, 6562, 6564, 6566, 6567, 6568, 6569, 6571, 6572, 6574, 6575, 6603, 6605, 6606, 6608, 6609, 6612, 6613, 6614, 6616, 6620, 6623, 6625, 6627, 6628, 6630, 6631, 6632, 6635, 6638, 6639, 6640, 6642, 6646, 6701, 6705, 6707, 6710, 6711, 6712, 6713, 6714, 6716, 6718, 6720, 6721, 6722, 6725, 6726, 6728, 6731, 6733, 6740, 6743, 6751, 6753, 6754, 6758, 6760, 6762, 6765, 6770, 6798, 6799
